Claudio Coppola

PhD in Robotics, Machine Learning Expert

Robotics researcher focused on AI. Experienced in Machine Learning for Robotics and Computer Vision. Aiming to create a positive impact on the world using Artificial Intelligence.

For additional information, please consult my linkedin profile - linkedin.com/in/clcoppola

Experience

Machine Learning Applied Scientist

Amazon

July 2022 - Current London, UK

Scoped, Developed and deployed cost estimation and volume forecasting solutions for the Amazon Transportation Services Less-Than-Truckload product working in direct contact with business at all the stages of development. Project estimated entitlement: (4M\$).

Postdoctoral Researcher

Queen Mary University of London

May 2019 – June 2022

 Contributed to and Coordinated the work of PhD/MSc students for the EPSRC MAN³ Project, involving Shadow Robotics, Ocado and Deepmind.

• Conducted research on learning by demonstration for robot manipulation by building a *teleoperation platform* and a demonstration segmentation system.

LD11 Cohort Member

Entrepreneur First

Oct 2018 – Jan 2019 **London, UK**

Took the role of CTO cooperating at the ideation of the start-up, public speaking, customer and product development and market analysis.

Lead Data Scientist

Buzzoole

April 2018 – Oct 2018 Napoli, Italy

Led the data science team, worked on several Machine Learning Projects central to raise \$8.9M funding for the company to improve the product.

Research Associate

University of Lincoln

May 2017 — May 2018 Lincoln, UK

- Developed state-of-the-art Human Activity Recognition and Re-identification models used in the EU H2020 research projects ENRICHME and FLOBOT.
- Teaching Assistant for courses of Artificial Intelligence and Robotics.

Other Experiences

- KPMG Business Intelligence Consultant (Jan-Jun 2014):
 Automated daily BI maintenance tasks with a speed-up above 90% and developed SQL queries to generate BI reports.
- 2Watch Data Scientist Contractor (Jan-Dec 2020):
 Developed an OCR system to extract information from photos of gaming dashboards.

Technical Skills

- Machine Learning & AI Deep Learning, SVM, Bayesian Optimization, Ensembles, GMM, HMM, K-Means, PCA, Kalman/Particle Filters.
- Frameworks ROS, Pytorch, Scikit-learn, Keras, Tensorflow, Docker, React, Kinect SDK2, OpenCV, React.
- Methodological Computer Vision, Machine Learning, Signal Processing, Control Theory, Software Engineering, Optimization, Scientific writing.

Programming Skills

Proficient: Python, Matlab.

Familiar with: C, C++, C#, Java, Javascript,

SQL.

Certifications

Machine Learning - Stanford University on Coursera, Prof. Andrew Ng

Deep Learning Specialization *deeplearning.ai* on Coursera, Prof. Andrew Ng.

Deep Reinforcement Learning Nanodegree Udacity

Awards

London, UK

2022 PD Enrichment Awards 2022 Al-Net PostDoc Awards 2020 Hult regionals winner 2020 CORSMAL challenge winner Alan Turing I. DAAD Hult F.

QMUL

Education

PhD in Robotics University of Lincoln

Jul 2014 - Aug 2018

Lincoln, UK

- Built Human Social Activity and interaction recognition systems based on RGB-D data.
- Associated with the EU H2020 Projects ENRICHME and STRANDS
- AI: SVM, GMM, Ensemble, Bayesian Nets, Random Forest, Deep Learning, Clustering.

MSc cum Laude in Computer Science Engineering

University Federico II of Napoli

Oct 2011 - Dec 2013

Napoli, IT

- Top 5% Student
- Focus: Computer Vision, Machine Learning, Signal Processing.
- Thesis: Iris Liveness detection for authentication systems based on Iris Recognition

BSc in Computer Science Engineering

University Federico II of Napoli

Oct 2011 - Dec 2013

Napoli, IT

- Top 5% Student
- Thesis: Algorithm and systems for voice recognition.
- Focus: Software Engineering, Artificial Intelligence, Control.

London, UK

Publications & Invited Talks

Invited Talks

- "Human Activity Recognition and Monitoring" Symposium of the British Machine Vision Association 2017 (BMVA), London, UK.
- Learning Human Actions: from Perception to Robot Learning, University of Leeds, UK
- Learning Human Actions: from Perception to Robot Learning, University of Lincoln, UK

Journals

- [1] Xompero, A., Donaher, S., Iashin, V., Palermo, F., Solak, G., Coppola, C., ... & Cavallaro, A. (2022). The CORSMAL benchmark for the prediction of the properties of containers. IEEE Access.
- [2] Siddiqui, M. S., Coppola, C., Solak, G., & Jamone, L. (2021). Grasp Stability Prediction for a Dexterous Robotic Hand Combining Depth Vision and Haptic Bayesian Exploration. Frontiers in Robotics and AI, 237.
- [3] Coppola, C., Cosar, S., Faria, D., & Bellotto, N. (2019). Social Activity Recognition on Continuous RGB-D Video Sequences. International Journal of Social Robotics, 1–15.

Conferences & Workshops

- [4] Dawood A. B., Coppola C. & Althoefer K.(2023). Learning Decoupled Multi-touch Force Estimation, Localization and Stretch for Soft Capacitive E-skin. IEEE International Conference of Robotics and Automation (ICRA) 2023
- [5] Coppola C., & Jamone L.(2022). Master of Puppets: Multi-modal Robot Activity Segmentation from Teleoperated Demonstrations. In 2022 IEEE Conference on Development and Learning (ICDL).
- [6] Coppola C., Solak G. & Jamone L.(2022). A portable and affordable system for the teleoperation of dexterous robotic hands using Leap Motion hand tracking and vibrotactile feedback. In 2022 31st IEEE International Symposium on Robot and Human Interactive Communication (RO-MAN).
- [7] Zenha R., Denoun B., Coppola C. & Jamone L. (2021). Tactile Slip Detection in the Wild Leveraging Distributed Sensing of both Normal and Shear Forces. In Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS), 2021 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on.
- [8] Xompero, A., Donaher, S., Iashin, V., Palermo, F., Solak, G., Coppola, C., ... & Cavallaro, A. (2021). Multi-modal estimation of the properties of containers and their content: survey and evaluation. arXiv preprint arXiv:2107.12719.
- [9] Siddiqui, M. S., Coppola, C., Solak, G., & Jamone, L. (2021, September). Discovering Stable Robot Grasps for Unknown Objects in Presence of Uncertainty Using Bayesian Models. In Annual Conference Towards Autonomous Robotic Systems (pp. 46-55). Springer, Cham.
- [10] Iashin V. and Palermo F. and Solak G. and Coppola C. (2020). Filling Mass Estimation Using Multi-modal Observations of Human-robot Handovers. CoRR, abs/2012.01311.
- [11] Coppola, C., Cosar, S., Faria, D., & Bellotto, N. (2017). Automatic detection of human interactions from RGB-D data for social activity classification. In 2017 26th IEEE International Symposium on Robot and Human Interactive Communication (RO-MAN) (pp. 871-876).
- [12] Fernandez-Carmona, M., Cosar, S., Coppola, C., & Bellotto, N. (2017). Entropy-based abnormal activity detection fusing RGB-D and domotic sensors. In 2017 IEEE International Conference on Multisensor Fusion and Integration for Intelligent Systems (MFI) (pp. 42-48).
- [13] Coppola, C., Faria, D., Nunes, U., & Bellotto, N. (2016). Social activity recognition based on probabilistic merging of skeleton features with proximity priors from RGB-D data. In Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS), 2016 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on (pp. 5055–5061).
- [14] Cosar, S., Coppola, C. & Bellotto, N. (2017). Volume-based Human Re-identification with RGB-D Cameras. In VISIGRAPP (4: VISAPP) (pp. 389–397).
- [15] Coppola, C., Krajnik, T., Duckett, T., & Bellotto, N. (2016). Learning temporal context for activity recognition. In European Conference on Artificial Intelligence (ECAI2016).
- [16] Coppola, C., Mozos, O., Bellotto, N.(2015). Applying a 3d qualitative trajectory calculus to human action recognition using depth cameras. In IEEE/RSJ IROS Workshop on Assistance and Service Robotics in a Human Environment.